Developer Advocate Grant Smith

Community Engagement and Content Creation

- 2022–2022 **Meetup Presenter**, *East Bay Machine Learning Meetup*, Virtual Has presented five times within the last year on various deep learning topics.
- 2022–2022 **Career Fair Representative**, *Security Benefit*, Various, KS

 Go-to representative for career fairs. Found and hired two interns, one of whom we hired full time, and the other of whom was my report and we are hoping to hire full time at the end of the year.
- 2022–2022 **Content Creator (Personal)**, *YouTube, Medium, Github, Kaggle, GeoGebra,* Has lightly been making Youtube videos and other content for the last 6 years.

Teaching Experience

- 2021–2022 **Data Analytics Boot Camp Instructor**, *EdX / Ohio State University*, Virtual Taught an online data analytics boot camp.
 - 5 star rating from each student in both review to EdX and Rate My Professor.
 - O Taught the class in the evenings while working full time.
 - 2022 **Pre Calculus Instructor**, *The University of Kansas*, Lawrence, KS Taught two classes of pre-calculus at The University of Kansas.
 - O Also 5 star rating from each student in both review to KU and Rate My Professor.

Work Experience

2022-Present Quantitative Developer, Security Benefit, Topeka, KS

Worked on our derivative valuation software.

- Initiated our documentation effort.
- Was part of our leadership group.
- 2020–2021 **Business Intelligence Developer**, *Black and Veatch*, Overland Park, KS Developed business intelligence solutions with Power BI and other BI and data engineering tools.
- 2019–2020 **Software Developer, Implementation Engineer**, Atonix Digital (Black and Veatch Subsidiary, now owned by Prometheus Group), Overland Park, KS

 Began on the implementation team to onboard new clients. Worked way into role on the development
- 2016–2019 **Data Manager, Chemical Engineer**, *Black and Veatch*, Overland Park, KS Began career as chemical engineer, but fell in love with programming. Redirected career toward that goal.

Education

2022 **Certified Cloud Practitioner**, *AWS*, Virtual

Earned Amazon Web Services Cloud Practitioner Certification.

2022 **Mathematics, M.A.**, *The University of Kansas*, Lawrence, KS Spent a semeter as a master's student. Left early for quant opportunity.

2012–2016 Chemical Engineering, B.S., The University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS

- O Business minor.
- Leadership certificate.
- O Dean's List for academic achievement. 3.85 GPA.
- O Was the president of his fraternity, which included managing 100+ students, 70+ of which lived in the house.

Comments From Peers

Benefit

- Security O What I really appreciate about Grant is how proactive he is. Simply put, he makes problems go away.
 - O I have not met a more team-first person than Grant.
 - I keep finding Grant's documentation in here and it keeps saving my butt.

- Students O Super friendly, kind, nice and caring. You can tell he truly loves what he does! Definitely recommend and take again.
 - O He has an uncanny ability to sense when your ADHD brain begins to zone out and immediately refocuses the class.